<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The blog of Rob de Kleine</title>
 <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io"/>
 <updated>2019-10-07T13:05:09+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://sjmst5.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Rob de Kleine</name>
   <email>robdekleinepkg@outlook.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>HOLIDAY</title>
   <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/HOLIDAY"/>
   <updated>2019-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/HOLIDAY</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;long-holiday&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LONG HOLIDAY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2019/08/keyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;keyboard&quot; title=&quot;keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;starting-18-november-2019-im-on-holiday&quot;&gt;Starting 18 November 2019 i’m on holiday.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you guys back in 2020!!
Greetings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2019/08/frikandel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;frikandel&quot; title=&quot;A cute del&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Storage Server</title>
   <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/Storage-Server"/>
   <updated>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/Storage Server</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;freenas&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FreeNAS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2019/08/keyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;keyboard&quot; title=&quot;keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;install&quot;&gt;Install&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freenas.org/download-freenas-release/&quot;&gt;FreeNAS&lt;/a&gt; and burn the iso on an (flash)drive with &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/&quot;&gt;Win32DiskImager&lt;/a&gt;.
Boot into the install drive and follow the instructions.
After installation the ip of the web user interface will be prompted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter your web user interface, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Username = root&lt;/code&gt; did you set your pw to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;toor&lt;/code&gt;😉?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;set-an-account&quot;&gt;Set an account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Accounts from the left panel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Users.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Users” section, click the Add button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill out the name, username, and password fields.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Save button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-an-storage-pool&quot;&gt;Create an storage pool&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Storage from the left panel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Pools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Pools” section, click the Add button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the Create new pool option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Create Pool button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type a name for the new storage pool — for example, StorageCollection1.
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;(Optional) Check the Encryption option.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the Confirm option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the I Understand button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Available Disks” section, select the drives that will participate in the storage pool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Right arrow button to add the drives to the “Data VDevs” section.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Data VDevs” column, use the drop-down menu and select the Raid-Z option to create a storage pool with redundancy and performance.
These are all the available layout options when setting up a pool with FreeNAS:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Raid-Z — single drive parity similar to RAID5.
Raid-Z2 — double drive parity similar to RAID6.
Raid-Z3 — which uses triple drive parity.
Stripe — data is shared on two drives (similar to RAID0).
Mirror — copies data on two drives (similar to RAID1, but not limited to 2 disks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Create button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Confirm option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Create Pool button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Download Recovery Key button if you selected the “Encryption” option, and then the Done button once you saved the file key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-an-windows-samba-share&quot;&gt;Create an Windows (Samba) Share&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Storage from the left panel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Pools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the settings (three-dotted) button next to the pool and select the Add Dataset option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type a name for the dataset — for example, DataSetOne.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Share Type” section, select the Windows option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Save button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the settings (three-dotted) button next to the dataset and select the Edit Permissions option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “User” section, use the drop-down menu and select the user that you created earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Save button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Sharing from the left panel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Windows (SMB) Shares.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Samba” section, click the Add button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the folder, navigate, and select the dataset you created earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Name” field, type a name for the folder you’re sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Save button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Enable Service button (if applicable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mount-the-share-on-windows&quot;&gt;Mount the share on Windows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open File Explorer on Windows 10.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on This PC from the left panel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the “Computer” tab, click the Map network drive button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a drive letter, but you can leave the default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the Folder field, type the path of network share on FreeNAS — for example, \10.1.2.158\Data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the Reconnect at sign-in option if you want to permanently connect to the FreeNAS location.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the Connect using different credentials option in the case you need another account credentials to access the files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Finish button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sign-in with the FreeNAS user account credentials you created earlier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you complete the steps, you can go to “This PC” to access the newly FreeNAS mapped drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, if you don’t want to map the folder in File Explorer, you can simply browse to the shared folder typing the path in the address bar, and signing in with the FreeNAS credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sync-your-files-with-dropbox&quot;&gt;Sync your files with Dropbox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to your Dropbox account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on the three dots on the lower right-hand side, and choose Developers. 3. Click Create apps to open the DBX platform and create an app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This process is needed to create a unique access token which FreeNAS and TrueNAS use to identify the account and files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After the app is created, generate the key by clicking Generate access token.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to your FreeNAS web user interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on System from the left panel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Cloud Credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Add button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type a name for the Dropbox account — for example, Dropbox 2TB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set Provider to Dropbox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Copy in your access token.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Save button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Tasks from the left panel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on Cloud Sync Tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select your Dropbox account and schedule a sync task.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the folder on the FreeNAS system. This can be an existing dataset to sync to Dropbox or a new dataset to back up files in your Dropbox share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: Set the kind of sync needed (Push or Pull) and how to transfer the content: Sync, Copy, or Move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sync copies any changes from the source system to the destination.
Copy copies new files. Files deleted on the host are not deleted on the destination.
Move copies files to the destination, then deletes them from the source after the transfer is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2019/08/frikandel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;frikandel&quot; title=&quot;A cute del&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>PI Network Bridge</title>
   <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/PI-Network-Bridge"/>
   <updated>2019-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/PI Network Bridge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;pi-network-brige&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pi Network Brige&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2019/08/keyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;keyboard&quot; title=&quot;keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;easy-raspberry-pi-wifi-bridge&quot;&gt;Easy Raspberry Pi WiFi Bridge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Raspberry Pi WiFi bridge is one of the best ways of providing internet access to a device that only supports an Ethernet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Pi WiFi Bridge
In this tutorial, we will show you how to setup a WiFi bridge, and how to setup dnsmasq correctly to allow any device to connect through your Pi without issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to keep in mind that you will not see speeds as good as what you would with a direct connection to your router. As there is some overhead with the connection having to run through the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to do this tutorial you will need either a WiFi dongle or a Raspberry Pi 3 with the inbuilt WiFi module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial can be combined with our basic VPN access point, you can find the tutorial on how to set that up directly after this tutorial. Basically, it will show how to setup a OpenVPN client and redirect all traffic through that client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note: This tutorial will require some slight changes if you decide to go down the VPN route, we will explain the necessary changes needed at the end of this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equipment List
Below are all the bits and pieces that I used for this Raspberry Pi WiFI bridge tutorial, you will need A Wireless internet connection to be able to complete this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended
 Raspberry Pi 2 or 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micro SD Card&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wifi dongle (The Pi 3 has WiFi inbuilt)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethernet Connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optional
 Raspberry Pi Case&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the WiFi Bridge
To setup the Raspberry Pi Wifi bridge we will be utilizing the dnsmasq package, this package handles most of the grunt work for this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dnsmasq is a package that acts as both a local DHCP server and a local DNS server. We utilize this package so that we can assign IP addresses and process DNS requests through the Raspberry Pi itself and act like a router.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the bonuses to utilizing dnsmasqis that it is very easy to configure while being somewhat lightweight in comparison to the isc-dhcp-server and bind9 packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember for this tutorial you will need to have an active WiFi router to connect to and an ethernet device you intend on bridging the Wi-Fi connection to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before we get started with installing and setting up our packages, we will first run an update on the Raspberry Pi by entering the following two commands into the terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get upgrade&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With that done we can now install the one and only package we will be utilizing, run the following command to install dnsmasq.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install dnsmasq&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before we get too far ahead of ourselves, we should setup the wlan0 connection that we plan on using. If you have already setup your wireless connection then you can skip ahead to step 5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise open up the wpa_supplicant file by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo nano /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Within this file add the following, making sure you replace the ssid with the name of the network you want to connect to and replace the psk value with the password for that network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;network={
        ssid=”networkname”
        psk=”networkpassword”
}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With the wireless network now setup to correctly connect we can proceed with setting up our eth0 interface. This will basically force it to use a static IP address, not setting this up can cause several issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this we need to modify the dhcpcd.conf file by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo nano /etc/dhcpcd.conf
 Important Note: If you’re on Raspbian stretch then wlan0 and eth0 may need to be changed if predictable network names is turned on. Use the ifconfig command to see the new names, they’re likely quite long and will contain the MAC address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you update these for all the commands in this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Within this file we need to add the following lines, make sure you replace eth0 with the correct interface of your ethernet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interface eth0
static ip_address=192.168.220.1/24
static routers=192.168.220.0
Now we can save and quit out of the file by pressing Ctrl+X then pressing Y and then Enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With our changes made to dhcpcd configuration we should now restart the service by running the following command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo service dhcpcd restart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before we get started with modifying dnsmasq’s configuration we will first make a backup of the original configuration by running the following command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo mv /etc/dnsmasq.conf /etc/dnsmasq.conf.orig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With the original configuration now backed up and moved out of the way we can now move on and create our new configuration file by typing the command below into the terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo nano /etc/dnsmasq.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now that we have our new file created we want to add the lines below, these lines basically tell the dnsmasq package how to handle DNS and DHCP traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;interface=eth0       # Use interface eth0&lt;br /&gt;
listen-address=192.168.220.1   # Specify the address to listen on&lt;br /&gt;
bind-interfaces      # Bind to the interface
server=8.8.8.8       # Use Google DNS&lt;br /&gt;
domain-needed        # Don’t forward short names&lt;br /&gt;
bogus-priv           # Drop the non-routed address spaces.&lt;br /&gt;
dhcp-range=192.168.220.50,192.168.220.150,12h # IP range and lease time
Now we can save and quit out of the file by pressing Ctrl+Xthen pressing Y and then Enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We now need to configure the Raspberry Pi’s firewall so that it will forward all traffic from our eth0 connection over to our wlan0 connection. Before we do this we must first enable ipv4p IP Forwarding through the sysctl.conf configuration file, so let’s begin editing it with the following command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo nano /etc/sysctl.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Within this file you need to find the following line, and remove the # from the beginning of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#net.ipv4.ip_forward=1
Replace with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;net.ipv4.ip_forward=1
Now we can save and quit out of the file by pressing Ctrl+X then pressing Y and then Enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now since we don’t want to have to wait until the next reboot before the configuration is loaded in, we can run the following command to enable it immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo sh -c “echo 1 &amp;gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_forward”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now that IPv4 Forwarding is enabled we can reconfigure our firewall so that traffic is forwarded from our eth0 interface over to our wlan0 connection. Basically this means that anyone connecting to the ethernet will be able to utilize our wlan0 internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands to add our new rules to the iptable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o wlan0 -j MASQUERADE&lt;br /&gt;
sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i wlan0 -o eth0 -m state –state RELATED,ESTABLISHED -j ACCEPT&lt;br /&gt;
sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i eth0 -o wlan0 -j ACCEPT
 Note: If you get errors when entering the above lines simply reboot the Pi using sudo reboot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Of course iptables are flushed on every boot of the Raspberry Pi so we will need to save our new rules somewhere so they are loaded back in on every boot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save our new set of rules run the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo sh -c “iptables-save &amp;gt; /etc/iptables.ipv4.nat”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now with our new rules safely saved somewhere we need to make this file be loaded back in on every reboot. The most simple way to handle this is to modify the rc.local file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to begin editing the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo nano /etc/rc.local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now we are in this file, we need to add the line below. Make sure this line appears above exit 0. This line basically reads the settings out of our iptables.ipv4.nat file and loads them into the iptables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;exit 0
Add Above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iptables-restore &amp;lt; /etc/iptables.ipv4.nat
Now we can save and quit out of the file by pressing Ctrl+X then pressing Y and then Enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally all we need to do is start our dnsmasq service. To do this, all you need to do is run the following command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo service dnsmasq start&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you should finally have a fully operational Raspberry Pi WiFi Bridge, you can ensure this is working by plugging any device into its Ethernet port, the bridge should provide an internet connection to the device you plugged it into.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure everything will run smoothly it’s best to try rebooting now. This will ensure that everything will successfully re-enable when the Raspberry Pi is started back up. Run the following command to reboot the Raspberry Pi:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo reboot
 Setting up the Raspberry Pi WiFi Bridge with a VPN
This tutorial is fully compatible with the basic VPN router tutorial. However there is one small change you will have to make in step 13, rather than using the commands showcased there, run the commands below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically the main change you will see here is that instead of redirecting the traffic from wlan0 through the tunnel we will be redirecting the traffic from our eth0 connection to the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sudo iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o tun0 -j MASQUERADE
sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i tun0 -o eth0 -m state –state RELATED,ESTABLISHED -j ACCEPT
sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i eth0 -o tun0 -j ACCEPT
The rest of the VPN Access Point tutorial can be done without any other changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by now you should have a fully operational Raspberry Pi WiFi Bridge. If you come across any issues or have some feedback related to this tutorial, then please don’t hesitate to leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/2019/08/frikandel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;frikandel&quot; title=&quot;A cute del&quot; /&gt;
ref: https://pimylifeup.com/raspberry-pi-wifi-bridge/&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ubuntu 18.04</title>
   <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/ubuntu"/>
   <updated>2019-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/ubuntu</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu.com/download/desktop&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; and just install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;root-access&quot;&gt;Root access&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal by pressing Ctrl+Alt+T (Ctrl+C to clean) &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo -i (or sudo -s)&lt;/code&gt; when promted provide your password. After successful login, the $ prompt would change to # indicating that you are logged in as root user on Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ssh&quot;&gt;SSH&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apt install ssh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirm the SSH server is up and running by executing the command bellow. 
Look for keyword &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Active: active (running)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;service ssh status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an event that you need to temporarily disable SSH or restart:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;service ssh stop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start again run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;service ssh start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to completely disable SSH after reboots 
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;systemctl disable ssh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable SSH again
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;systemctl enable ssh&lt;/code&gt;
Config SSH port
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nano /etc/ssh/sshd_config&lt;/code&gt;
remove the # before the line you want to edit
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;port 5022&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PermitRootLogin yes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to save and exit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl + X&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Y&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to restart ssh or reboot😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ifconfig&quot;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable ifconfig you need to install net-tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apt install net-tool&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;samba-public-local-share&quot;&gt;Samba (public local) share&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now where going to set up an Folder that can be found in the network with Samba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open an Terminal and install
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apt-get install samba smbfs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configure samba
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nano /etc/samba/smb.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If necesary you can change your workgoup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;# Change this to the workgroup/NT-domain name your Samba server will part of
   workgroup = WORKGROUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Define the folders that you want to share&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-conf highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Public's share
&lt;/span&gt;[&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;MyPublicShare&lt;/span&gt;]
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;YOUR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;COMMENTS&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; = /&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;your&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;share&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;folder&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;only&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;guest&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ok&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart samba &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/init.d/smbd restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not already you can create the share folder: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mkdir /your-share-folder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the permissions: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chmod 0777 /your-share-folder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acces in Windows Explorer
Type: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\\&amp;lt;your-ip-address-to-ubuntu&amp;gt;\&amp;lt;your-share-folder&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you have troubles with your Firewall,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;the ports are: udp 137 &amp;amp; 138, tcp 139 &amp;amp; 445.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deluge&quot;&gt;Deluge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Install “Deluge” from the Ubuntu store)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open an Terminal and intall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apt install deluged deluge-console deluge-webui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run Deluge and check the box Preferences-&amp;gt;Daemon-&amp;gt;Allow Remote Connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd /etc/systemd/system/
touch deluged.service
nano /etc/systemd/system/deluged.service&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-conf highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Unit&lt;/span&gt;]
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Deluge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Bittorrent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Client&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Daemon&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deluged&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;After&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;network&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;online&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;
[&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Service&lt;/span&gt;]
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;simple&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deluge&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Group&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deluge&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;UMask&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;007&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ExecStart&lt;/span&gt;=/&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;usr&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bin&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;deluged&lt;/span&gt; -&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;d&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Restart&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;failure&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Time to wait before forcefully stopped.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;TimeoutStopSec&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;
[&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Install&lt;/span&gt;]
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;WantedBy&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;multi&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start Deluge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo systemctl start deluged&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, enable the Daemon at boot with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;systemctl enable deluged&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time to set up the user for Deluge Daemon. Use echo to push a new user to the configuration file. 
Change “user” to the name of the existing user on the system. Be sure that you enter the same password as your system user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: 10 means your system user has full access to modify Deluge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;echo &quot;user:password:10&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.config/deluge/auth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the user is correctly configured, kill the daemon and start it back up. This can be done with systemd or killall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo systemctl stop deluged&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo systemctl start deluged&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, enable the Deluge WebUI connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deluge-web --fork&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ufw-uncomplicatedfirewall&quot;&gt;UFW (UncomplicatedFirewall)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install UFW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apt-get install ufw&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check te status&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, it will probably tell you it is inactive. Whenever ufw is active, you’ll get a listing of the current rules that looks similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-conf highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Status&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;active&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;To&lt;/span&gt;               &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Action&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;From&lt;/span&gt;
--               ------      ----
&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;               &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ALLOW&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Anywhere&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow Connections
Example ssh:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow ssh&lt;/code&gt;
or
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow 22/tcp&lt;/code&gt;
or
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow 5022/tcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other samples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow www&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow 80/tcp&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow ftp&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow 21/tcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Port ranges:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow 1000:2000/tcp&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow 1000:2000/udp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IP addresses:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw allow from 192.168.255.255&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deny Connectios:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw deny 80/tcp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleting Rules:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw delete *********&lt;/code&gt;
sample
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw delete allow ssh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turn ufw on status verbose off and reset:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw enable&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw status&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw status verbose&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw disable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reset to default:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ufw reset&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Visual Studio Code</title>
   <link href="https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/visual-studio-code"/>
   <updated>2019-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://sjmst5.github.io/articles/visual-studio-code</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;install&quot;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/download&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; and install with “Windows integration”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extensions&quot;&gt;Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Extensions i have installed are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=CoenraadS.bracket-pair-colorizer&quot;&gt;Bracket Pair Colorizer&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=idleberg.emoji-code&quot;&gt;Emoji Code&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=eamodio.gitlens&quot;&gt;GitLens&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=PKief.material-icon-theme&quot;&gt;Material Icon Theme&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=Equinusocio.vsc-material-theme&quot;&gt;Material Theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional&quot;&gt;Additional&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;An Github account&lt;/a&gt;, For web storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/&quot;&gt;An Travis CI account&lt;/a&gt;, Testing before deploying the new/updated site online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitforwindows.org/&quot;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt;, Terminal in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the terminal create an ssh to github, install “Jakyll” and “Ruby (cli)”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
